<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Feldman</title>
    <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Scott Feldman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:57:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fellows Immunology Course</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:57:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</guid>
      <description>I developed this course modeled after my immunology training in fellowship. Instructional methodology employs a flipped classroom with active learning via worksheets prior to sessions, which focus on discussion of material, addressing questions, and exploring some topics in greater depth. Topics are generally organized in the order of the textbook. Currently I am the main instructor as well, leading about 80% of the sessions. As the course grows and repeats, I anticipate senior fellows leading sessions, and expanding to include other faculty who feel comfortable leading any topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Student Invited Lecture</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/medical-student-invited-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/medical-student-invited-lecture/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Student Small Groups</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/medical-student-small-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/medical-student-small-groups/</guid>
      <description>Evaluations “Dr. Feldman has made MDM small groups extremely interactive, and I feel as though I really learn the material both by preparing for these sessions and due to his teaching/review of concepts.” “Dr. Feldman was an excellent MDM leader; he provided examples of times he used MDM principles in treating actual patients, and did a great job of explaining principles which the group didn&amp;rsquo;t understand.” “Dr. Feldman does a great job in guiding our group through the assignment, emphasizing the important aspects and relating it to what is clinically relevant in reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I grew up in Ft. Lauderdale, Florida. I went to medical school in Chicago and fell in love with the city, although Philadelphia is growing on me since August 2017. When I’m not seeing patients or teaching, I like enjoy running, biking, cooking, finding a new ethnic restaurant, and sharing fun (anonymous, HIPAA-friendly) stories of funny, interesting, memorable patients. Medium-term, I would like to be course director of basic immunology for first-year medical students, and allergy/immunology fellowship program director.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas of Teaching Competence</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/areas/</guid>
      <description> Allergic Diseases and Management Basic Immunology Clinical Immunology Medical Decision Making (including basic biostatistics) and Clinical Reasoning Assorted topics in Medical Education (creating goals/objectives, basics of curricular design, assessment, and feedback)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honors &amp; Awards</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/honors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/honors/</guid>
      <description> 2017 Northwestern Teaching Award for Basic Science, “Stellar Teaching Contribution” 2016- 2017 Academic Year End Teaching Award, Outstanding Fellow Educator 2012 Granville Bennett Award for Medical Education  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Training, Licensure, and Certification</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/training/</guid>
      <description>Education  2002 B.S. Biochemistry, University of Florida 2012 M.D. University of Illinois at Chicago College of Medicine 2012 Ph.D. Immunology, Univ. of IL at Chicago College of Medicine  Postdoctoral Training  2012-2013 Intern in Internal Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY 2013-2015 Resident in Internal Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY 2015-2017 Fellow in Allergy / Immunology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL 2016-pres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positions &amp; Service</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/positions/</guid>
      <description>Positions  2017 Assistant Professor of Medicine 2017 Associate Fellowship Program Director 2017 Course Director, Fellows Immunology Course 2016-2017 Chief Fellow  Scholarship  Feldman, S (Chapter Co-author, Chapter 7: Pharmacology and Therapeutics.) 2016 ACAAI Review for the Allergy &amp;amp; Immunology Boards: Third Edition. Dr. David Stukus, Editor.  Administrative Service  2017 Penn Allergy / Immunology Fellowship Self-Study Committee 2013-2015 Curriculum Committee, Internal Medicine Residency 2010-2012 Ad Hoc Committee on Curriculum Transformation, Member 2008-2010 MSTP Admissions Committee, Member</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Development in Medical Education and Leadership</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/profdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/profdev/</guid>
      <description> 2017 ACAAI Leadership Summit: Generation Next Participant 2015-2017 Medical Education Clinical Scholars Program, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL 2014 Harvard-Macy Institute Program for Post-Graduate Trainees: Future Academic Clinician-Educators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected curriculum vitæ</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/cv/</guid>
      <description>Positions in Medical Education  2017Assistant Professor of Medicine 2017Associate Fellowship Program Director 2017Course Director, Fellows Immunology Course 2016–20172016-2017 Chief Fellow  Curriculum Development  2017Fellows Immunology Course 2017M3 Immunology Online Module 2013–2015Medical Education Track for Internal Medicine Residency Program at Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Co-founder
 Co-developed curriculum outline and assessment methods Facilitated implementation of pilot track year   2010MSTP Back-to-M3 Student Transition Course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>This is my philosophy of teaching that I will update as I think more about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M3 Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</guid>
      <description>As a Fellow at Northwestern, I developed a five-part video series for a “flipped classroom” where students watched lectures before in-person sections designed to reinforce what they had learned and give immediate feedback on their understanding of the material.
Antibodies and Isotypes — What do antibodies do?  Lymphocyte Development — How do B cells develop? (05:20)  B Cell Activation — How are B cells activated? (05:50) Immunodeficiencies — (Part 1 of 2) (05:54)​ Immunodeficiencies — (Part 2 of 2) (04:04) Evaluations   “Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M3 Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</guid>
      <description>As a Fellow at Northwestern, I developed a five-part video series for a “flipped classroom” where students watched lectures before in-person sections designed to reinforce what they had learned and give immediate feedback on their understanding of the material.
Antibodies and Isotypes — What do antibodies do?  Lymphocyte Development — How do B cells develop? (05:20)  B Cell Activation — How are B cells activated? (05:50) Immunodeficiencies — (Part 1 of 2) (05:54)​ Immunodeficiencies — (Part 2 of 2) (04:04) Evaluations   “Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>