<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Education Portfolio on Scott Feldman</title>
    <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Education Portfolio on Scott Feldman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fellows Immunology Course</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:57:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</guid>
      <description>I developed this course modeled after my immunology training in fellowship. Instructional methodology employs a flipped classroom with active learning via worksheets prior to sessions, with learning sessions focused on discussing material, addressing questions, and exploring some topics in greater depth. Topics are generally organized in the order of the textbook. Currently I am the main instructor as well, leading about 80% of the sessions. As the course grows and repeats, I anticipate senior fellows leading sessions, and expanding to include other faculty who feel comfortable leading the discussion of any topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mimicry? Connecting The Basic &amp; Clinical Science of Allergy &amp; Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/uic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/uic/</guid>
      <description>In summer 2017, to celebrat the 10-year anniversary of my MD/PhD training program obtaining NIH-funding as an MSTP, I was invited to give the keynote address at this program, with a dinner seminar for the students. I used the opportunity to highlight why I chose my specialty with real clinical cases, review some unanswered research questions, discuss some recent groundbreaking papers in therapeutics and management, and finally to demonstrate and role model some techniques in medical education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/mdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/mdm/</guid>
      <description>At Northwestern University in the fall of 2016 and the spring of 2017, I led a small group for first-year medical students as part of the Medical Decision Making course. I had 3 different groups of 10-12 students, each for 5 sessions on average every other week (then instructors would rotate groups). Topics included Diagnostics, Advanced Decision Making, Case Control and Cohorts, Risk Harm and Association, Prognosis, Screening, Threshold Actions, Clinical Prediction Rules, Decision Analysis, Cost Effective Analysis, Guidelines &amp;amp; Policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Curriculum Development &amp; Direct Teaching</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/other/</guid>
      <description>Misc. Older Curriculum Development 2013-2015 Medical Education Track for Internal Medicine Residency Program at Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Co-founder Co-developed curriculum outline and assessment methods Facilitated implementation of pilot track year
2010 MSTP Back-to-M3 Student Transition Course Co-created a transition course Developed and organized lectures Designed and implemented evaluations
Misc. Older Direct Teaching: Lectures and Small Groups Pointer.jpg 2011-2012 Small group leader in Essentials of Clinical Medicine MSTP group, UIC College of Medicine 2008-2012 Instructor for Providing Healthcare to your LGBT Patients, UIC College of Medicine 2008 Teaching Assistant for Graduate Immunology, UIC College of Medicine 2006-2012 Quarterly reviews for M1 Histology course, UIC College of Medicine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic &amp; Clinical Immunology for Senior Medical Students</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</guid>
      <description>As a Fellow at Northwestern, I developed a five-part video series for a “flipped classroom” where students watched lectures before in-person sections designed to reinforce what they had learned and give immediate feedback on their understanding of the material.
This is the Online Module: 
These are the videos I created with Lightboard embedded within the above online module.
Antibodies and Isotypes What do antibodies do? (04:35)
 Lymphocyte Development How do B cells develop?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M1 Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m1immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m1immunology/</guid>
      <description>Since joining the faculty at Unversity of Pennsylvania, I co-led an M1 Immunology small group for 6 session in the fall of 2017. 18 students led themselves through immunology cases prepared by the course directors, and I facilitated discussion of the material.
In the fall of 2016, I was an instructor in the Basic Immunology course for M1 students at Northwestern University Medical School. I gave the large group lectures on Effector Functions of Humoral Immunity, Mucosal Immunology, and Immunity to Microbes to the class of ~150 students, who either attended in person and/or watched online.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>