<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Education Portfolio on Scott Feldman</title>
    <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Education Portfolio on Scott Feldman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fellows Immunology Course</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:57:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/fellowsimmunology/</guid>
      <description>I developed this course modeled after my immunology training in fellowship. Instructional methodology employs a flipped classroom with active learning via worksheets prior to sessions, with learning sessions focused on discussing material, addressing questions, and exploring some topics in greater depth. Topics are generally organized in the order of the textbook. Currently I am the main instructor as well, leading about 80% of the sessions. As the course grows and repeats, I anticipate senior fellows leading sessions, and expanding to include other faculty who feel comfortable leading the discussion of any topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mimicry? Connecting The Basic &amp; Clinical Science of Allergy &amp; Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/uic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/uic/</guid>
      <description>Link to UIC talk slides
Goals/objectives on medical education 2017 UIC COM MSTP “Molecular Mimicry? Connecting The Basic &amp;amp; Clinical Science of Allergy &amp;amp; Immunology” “This was awesome, I want to look into allergy and immunology now “ “Love humor, interaction. Love how you spoke about the specialty and broke that up throughout talk into small segments to keep us engaged.” “Great Seminar. I could tell you love what you are doing and cared about giving a good talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/mdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/mdm/</guid>
      <description>Sample lectures (?) - see Jessica Voth emails 2016-2017 Small group leader in Medical-Decision Making for M1 students, Northwestern University Medical School
Learner Evaluations “Dr. Feldman has made MDM small groups extremely interactive, and I feel as though I really learn the material both by preparing for these sessions and due to his teaching/review of concepts.” “Dr. Feldman was an excellent MDM leader; he provided examples of times he used MDM principles in treating actual patients, and did a great job of explaining principles which the group didn&amp;rsquo;t understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Curriculum Development &amp; Direct Teaching</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:23:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/other/</guid>
      <description>Misc. Older Curriculum Development 2013-2015 Medical Education Track for Internal Medicine Residency Program at Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Co-founder Co-developed curriculum outline and assessment methods Facilitated implementation of pilot track year
2010 MSTP Back-to-M3 Student Transition Course Co-created a transition course Developed and organized lectures Designed and implemented evaluations
Misc. Older Direct Teaching: Lectures and Small Groups Pointer.jpg 2011-2012 Small group leader in Essentials of Clinical Medicine MSTP group, UIC College of Medicine 2008-2012 Instructor for Providing Healthcare to your LGBT Patients, UIC College of Medicine 2008 Teaching Assistant for Graduate Immunology, UIC College of Medicine 2006-2012 Quarterly reviews for M1 Histology course, UIC College of Medicine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M1 Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m1immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m1immunology/</guid>
      <description>2017 M1 Immunology Small groups 2016 Instructor in Basic Immunology course for M1 students, Northwestern University Medical School
2017 University of Pennsylvania small group Feedback pending
2016 Northwestern University 3 lectures add learner guide add slides add MCQ example
more text even more text
i am adding more text to get it below the picture
am i below picture now?
let&amp;rsquo;s hope!
nope!
not yet
still going
waiting ot see if this does or does not fix?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M3 Immunology</title>
      <link>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfeldmanmdphd.github.io/EducatorPortfolio/pages/m3immunology/</guid>
      <description>As a Fellow at Northwestern, I developed a five-part video series for a “flipped classroom” where students watched lectures before in-person sections designed to reinforce what they had learned and give immediate feedback on their understanding of the material.
This is the Online Module
These are the videos I created with Lightboard embedded within the above online module.
Antibodies and Isotypes — What do antibodies do?  Lymphocyte Development — How do B cells develop?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>